♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
[Mongki] Atoy is missing.
[Red] But whoever did it,
I hope they kill Atoy.
Less problems for us.
- [Karla] Hey. Are you okay?
- I have to warn Aunt Audrey.
[Gavin] Daddy's men are here.
PREVIOUSLY
- [Karla] Where?
- Before we escaped,
my dad told me
Janine is not my real child.
Huh?
Ame, let's keep this between us. Please?
I need to talk to Atoy first.
Hasn't Atoy come home yet?
[Siony] There's been
so much violence here.
What if he got caught?
[Olga] He's involved
in a major terrorist group.
Do you think you can fight him?
Don't meddle in Uno and Mercado's plan!
[thumps, then thuds]
[grunts]
[Ibyang] Be good to Ibyang!
- [screams]
- [Ibyang] To everyone!
[in English] Mommy!
[in English] Today is the day you'll die.
[in English] And I'm a man of my word!
[music fades]
Hmm? Audrey, are you sure
you don't need help?
It's already done, see?
Do you really know how to cook?
[in English] You tell me. Mmm.
Hmm.
Hey!
The eggs aren't salty.
And the fried rice…
Delicious!
That's good.
I really do know how to cook.
Especially when I was in the States.
But when I came back here,
I didn't do it much.
[somber music playing]
When Janine arrived…
That's when I really became hands-on.
Because I wanted
to prepare everything she needed myself.
[pensive music playing]
[in English] Because I wanted
to take care of my daughter.
So, what now?
Audrey, you know, I think
you need to tell Janine the truth.
I know that too.
But it's not just me
she recognizes as a parent.
Atoy too.
[Audrey scoffs]
[music fades]
[Audrey] I don't know why
everything had to happen now.
Atoy is already going through so much,
and now we've added to it.
[melodramatic music playing]
Lord, please
let him come home safe.
It's Atoy.
He can handle it.
Let's just pray for him.
Everything will be okay.
Even what's happening with your family.
I hope so.
Especially for Janine.
I'm just worried about
what the child will feel.
[in English] I know she's been
through so much.
I don't want her to think she's alone.
Oh. Come on, let's eat.
Let's not waste what you cooked.
[suave theme music playing]
[motorcycle revving]
[sewing machine whirring]
[scratches]
[snipping]
[sewing machine clacking]
[gun cocks]
[gunshots]
[clacking]
[clicking]
[snipping]
[electronic blipping]
[music fades]
[line ringing]
[pensive music playing]
[in English] Sir.
[in English] Sir, I have the keys
to the bait vehicle,
and we'll proceed there.
[in English] I'll be approaching,
maybe in 20 minutes or less.
[Mercado on the phone, in English]
Good. Extraction team is in place
and on standby for immediate deployment.
[in English] Copy, sir.
[phone blips]
[music fades]
Huh? Huh? [chuckles]
Sorry. I changed clothes.
[in English] Changed outfit.
- [Olga] Oh, come on.
- Wow.
Let's go to the truck loader.
- Where is it?
- [Uno scoffs]
It wasn't part of our agreement
that you'd join the main operation, right?
People might see you there, Olga.
[scoffs]
[pensive music playing]
[stammers] I'll hide!
I'll lie down in the back, and--
Uno, you need more people!
Here I am!
[Olga] I'm all dressed up!
Okay, I'm ready
for the biggest action role of my life!
- [in English] Okay, let's go!
- [in English] Yes.
- Olga, no--
- Shh!
- No, you really can't!
Don't-- Don't worry.
[in English] Okay?
I underwent gun shooting training, and…
- I know how to fight.
- [in English] Okay.
Huh? Not that you asked,
but I guested as a goon
in Hearts on the Badge.
- Wow.
- And also in Encantadia.
A long time ago,
but I was a soldier there.
[smirks] All right.
But still, no.
You're still not included
because if something happens to you,
I'll be responsible.
Clear?
- But--
- But, please.
This operation has a timeline,
and you're causing delays.
It's really not possible,
and that's an order.
[tense music playing]
I braided my hair.
What a waste of an outfit.
- [music fades]
- [grunts, gasps]
- [pensive music playing]
- [huffs]
‪[Lily sighs]
Atoy. [sighs]
What will you do?
Whatever you're planning,
just do it to me.
[in English] Yes, Atoy.
[in English] You will go first.
[in English] We will save Lily.
She has the code for the laptop, but…
she will watch your death.
[in English] Start recording.
[device blips]
[ominous music playing]
[Atoy, in English] Please don't do this.
[in English] I'm begging you.
[in English] Please.
[in English] You're begging me?
[in English] Begging me is over.
[in English] I'm going to execute
both of you in front of the camera
and send it to the armed forces.
[in English] So that they'll know
that I am serious.
[music swells]
[Lily] Have mercy on him, please.
- Samir.
- [in English] Please.
[in English] Yes.
- [in English] Samir, have-- have mercy.
- [Atoy, in English] I'm begging you.
[in English] I will not
have mercy on this man!
[in English] And I will kill
many more men just like you
until I get my laptop back from
the military who took it from me!
Military?
What military?
What are you talking about, military?
[stammers] No…
I have nothing to do with…
with the military, not me!
Not me-- No-- No--
[in English] I don't know why
you keep lying to me,
ex-captain Anthony Padua
of the Army Ranger Regiment?
[suspenseful music playing]
‪[music fades]
[sinister music playing]
Boss, let's go through the main entrance!
Are you a new driver?
[Uno] Yes.
Where's your helper?
It's his day off, sir.
It's his birthday, he said.
Who?
It's still Jaymar, sir.
It's still Jaymar.
[guard 2] Ah!
So, it's Jaymar's birthday today.
Why didn't he invite us?
Sorry, sir.
But I need to go into the office now.
I still have many invoices to get signed.
Sorry, sir.
Wait!
It's not Jaymar's birthday today.
[rousing music playing]
- Hey, Emerson!
- Eat!
- Brother, eat!
Guys, eat first!
They said they got tired of my pares.
Good thing Sir Nestor will pay for it.
[teasing]
No problem!
- Go ahead!
- [shrieks]
Eat. It's my treat.
I won last night's ending game.
- [laughing]
- [cheering]
No, no, no. It's okay, it's okay.
Uh, we have somewhere to go.
Wa-- wait. Whe-- Where are you going?
Why do your faces look like that?
Looks like you're heading into a fight.
Seems like it.
We're going to rescue Atoy.
It's time we help Atoy.
Uno went in alone.
[Karla] Exactly.
You were told not to go
because it's dangerous, right?
We should leave that
to the experts, brother.
[Gavin, in English] Karla is right.
What if you end up fighting?
[in English] You're not trained.
And if you die?
Then we'll have a wake
here in our community.
- [in English] True.
- Yes.
And I'm scared of those things, brother.
My debut is coming up.
- What a waste of my 18 roses!
- Mmm.
You guys-- What kind…
What kind of town mates
and friends are you, huh?
Our brother needs help now.
[Paldo] Atoy is family.
What's wrong with you?
If any of you were in danger now,
Atoy wouldn't hesitate
to help you. You know that!
Now he needs help,
and you're chickening out?
If you don't want to, then don't!
Let's go, let's go.
- We'll go instead!
- [in English] Wait, wait, wait, wait!
For Brother Atoy, fine. I'm in.
Me too!
You're coming?
[in English] Of course.
[in English] I'm not gonna let you
go there without me.
Hmm. Really?
Now you decide to pair up?!
As for me, I'll fight for Brother Atoy.
- [Karla] Oh, Jona, oh.
- Oh, if you're fighting…
I'll join too!
- Oh.
- Mmm-hmm!
I'll join too!
[clears throat]
Um, fine.
I'll just pray for you.
Thank you.
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
[in English] What are we waiting for?!
All right, let's fight!
Charge!
- Charge?
- Let's go!
- All right! Charge!
- [clamoring]
All right, all right!
[music fades]
Hey, wait.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
- Where?
- Hold on.
- Do you even know where?
- Here.
- There! All together! Let's go there!
- [clamoring]
- [sneaky music playing]
[Karla] Come with us!
Wait!
Who's paying for this?!
[music fades]
[ominous music playing]
Get out!
[Uno] Ouch, sir.
Here's my ID, sir.
I'm really just a new driver, sir.
That's all he told me.
Put that down, sir.
Don't point the gun at me.
Where's your cell phone? Call him!
That's my problem, sir.
My phone is broken. I can't call him.
Put that down, sir.
You keep making excuses. Walk!
Oh, sir! Wait!
Walk!
Sir!
[grunting and groaning]
[music fades]
[gunshots in the distance]
[in English] Gunshots.
[in English] Let's go. You two, stay here.
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
[music fades]
Bro, I'll take over. You go outside.
[grunting and groaning]
- [grunting]
- [gasps]
[gunshots]
[grunting and groaning]
[groans, gasping]
I told you, Ibyang can be relied on.
[nervous chuckle]
- Ouch--
- Oh, sorry, sorry.
[Lily groans]
[music fades]
[action music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[groans]
[gunshots]
[foreboding music playing]
[grunts]
[in English] Sir, no visual of Padua.
But I'm under heavy attack!
I need immediate backup.
[pensive music playing]
[softly] Let's go.
[panting]
Atoy, what now? Where do we go?
Never mind.
We'll find another way. Let's go.
- [gunshots]
- [shrieks]
[gasping]
[thug] Where are you going?
You think you can escape?
Put your gun down.
Down!
All right, all right, all right.
[rousing music playing]
[grunts]
- [ominous music playing]
- [mutters]
Perfect timing.
[sighs]
[music fades]
All right. Take them!
[rousing music playing]
[groans]
[tense music playing]
[grunting and groaning]
[grunts and groans]
[tense music playing]
Lily, let's go.
[epic music playing]
[Ibyang] Janine!
- What are you doing?
- Give me that!
Come back here!
I just want to talk to my daddy!
And yesterday you didn't let me talk
to Daddy!
He called my phone!
And Tatoy said it's forbidden to call!
[suspicious music playing]
You're so stubborn!
But he's my daddy!
What's your problem?!
[music fades]
I'm not claiming him!
But if you call him,
the people who took him might find out
he has a cell phone!
You know, think before you act.
- Ah, really?
- [Ame] Psst, psst, psst!
- Really?!
- Oh no! You're fighting again, huh?
- You--
- [groans]
Sorry, Sister Ame! Sorry!
- Sorry.
- Janine, even until now,
you're still mean?!
So, what?!
Don't talk back to me like that, huh!
Apologize to Ibyang!
I won't apologize to her. Bleh!
And why should I listen to a dwarf?!
[Ibyang] Hey, hey, hey, hey.
You, that's wrong!
They're called little persons!
I don't care, and I won't apologize.
You know, this isn't even your house!
So, get out, you outsiders!
You know, you have such a bad attitude!
That's why you're not Atoy's child!
You probably got that attitude
from your real parents!
[Audrey] Ame!
[Ame] Audrey.
[in English] Mommy!
Audrey, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it.
I was just caught off guard.
Mommy, is what she said true?
I'm not your child?!
You're my mommy, right?!
[music fades]
Mommy, what?
You're my real mommy, right?
Why did she say that?
They're lying!
Make them leave!
Get out of here!
What they're saying isn't true!
[screaming]
- [pensive music playing]
- Janine, stop!
[heavy breathing]
Mommy. Mommy,
why are you siding with them?!
What they're saying isn't true!
So, you should take my side!
[sobbing]
Is what she said true?
I'm not your child?
[sobs]
Janine, let's talk first.
[somber music playing]
[in English] No!
[gasps]
[in English] Audrey, sorry, sorry.
Janine!
Wait.
Hmm, sit down here first.
Are you okay?
Uh, what's going on?
I'm… I'm confused.
Jan…
Janine isn't Aunt Audrey's daughter?
Oh, no.
Poor Janine.
[melodramatic music playing]
Wait.
So that means…
Tatoy isn't her daddy?
Yes.
But don't tell her yet.
Let Atoy and Audrey handle it.
Even if Janine fights with you.
Yes, Sister Ame.
Even if Janine is mean to me.
But who could be their real daughter?
[music swells]
[music fades]
[melancholic music playing]
Janine, my child?
Why are you still calling me your child?
I'm not your real child.
Don't say that.
But that's the truth.
Why did you lie to me?
Janine, I only found out
before we ran off to come here.
I didn't tell you yet, because…
I wanted to wait for Atoy.
So that's why Daddy doesn't love me,
because I'm not the real child.
That's not true.
He loves you, child.
Especially me.
[melodramatic music playing]
I'm so sorry this is happening.
Even I'm confused too.
But my view of you hasn't changed.
All the love I showed you, child…
It was all real.
I love you very much…
and I won't leave you.
I am here to love you
and to take care of you
as my own daughter.
[dramatic music playing]
I'm still your mommy, Janine.
No matter what happens.
[in English] You understand?
[tense music playing]
My saint is effective.
So fast.
[gunshots]
[in English] Let's go! Let's go!
[music fades]
[suspicious music playing]
Sir Alcaraz, are you okay there?
I'm still alive, sir.
[operative 1, in English] Men, move!
[operative 2] Go, go, go! Go! Faster!
[music fades]
[ominous music playing]
[footsteps approaching]
Huh?
Stay there.
[rousing music playing]
[electronic blipping]
[intense music playing]
[Atoy] She's Lily.
She's the decoder.
We need to secure Lily.
She might be targeted again.
‪UP NEXT
[Olga] Ibyang made that.
She said when I return,
we'll be whole again.
But I don't deserve that.
Why not?
You're Ibyang's real father.
[Martina] What now?
That means he might
already be with Audrey.
Good. Because if we find Atoy,
they'll probably be together in one place.
It'll be easier to erase them
from this world.
[Red] I'll take them all down at once.
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Like a bubble, like a bubble ♪
[music swells]
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias